<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UBports blog</title>
    <description>UBports blog. Ubuntu touch porting to android devices
</description>
    <link>http://blog.ubports.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.ubports.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 14:15:59 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 14:15:59 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is Ubuntu Touch Dead?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With news that dawned recently we’re expecting an influx of people joining our IRC to ask if we’re going to quit porting Ubuntu Touch now that it’s been announced to be dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, it’s not dead. Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=Ubuntu-Phone-Snap-Hold&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; over at Phoronix for a better look at the issue. Basically, Ubuntu Touch is just going to be rolled into Ubuntu Personal, the Snap-based version of Ubuntu. We’re going to start working on this as we have time, but it’s very experimental right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canonical is trying to focus their resources on Snaps, Unity 8, and Mir. We understand this and are not at all upset. It will bring the project forward as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, you guys should check out the Ubuntu Touch bountysource. You can find our tracker &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bountysource.com/trackers/45573416-ubports-android&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. There isn’t much there yet, but I for one find merit in having it around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the FP2 community, we also have a video showing our ability to place a call from a FP2 over GSM! Check it out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bz43mNw4AtU&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s about it for today. Ubuntu Touch is not dead. Come get in touch with us at #ubports on Freenode or the forum if you have any questions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Dalton (UniversalSuperBox)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/2017/01/06/is-ubuntu-touch-dead.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/2017/01/06/is-ubuntu-touch-dead.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy Holidays from UBPorts! (And FP2 fun!)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We here at UBPorts hope that you’re having/had an excellent set of holidays. As the year comes to a close, we’d like to thank all of our patrons, donors, and developers. You are what makes this project happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been busy around here, of course. Marius has returned for winter holiday at his school and my dashboard is looking busier than ever… an excellent sight when my name filled it up not too long ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d like to thank Smoose, a Netherlandic company specializing in open source software, for providing several Fairphone 2 smartphones to our developer community. Because of their generous donation, I have lots of news about the device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current daily builds for the Fairphone 2 have everything that you’ll find on &lt;a href=&quot;https://devices.ubports.com/#/FP2&quot;&gt;the device page&lt;/a&gt; PLUS some basic GSM support. You are able to connect to a GSM network with SIM 1 at least (I don’t have a second to test), send and receive SMS, and Marius reports that he has calling in a very experimental stage, though this may not be on system-image-server at the time of this writing. Mobile data doesn’t work quite yet, but we’re working on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To flash the development build, first note that it is not very stable and things break quite often. Now that that’s out of the way, you’ll need to first flash the recovery.img from &lt;a href=&quot;https://seafile.nigle.nl/d/62d505f0a7/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;,
Then run these commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;adb shell mount -a &amp;amp;&amp;amp;
adb shell mount /cache &amp;amp;&amp;amp;
ubuntu-device-flash --server=http://system-image.ubports.com touch --channel=ubuntu-touch/devel_rc-proposed --device=FP2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Edit: I had to put them in this terrible block because this Jekyll theme is annoying)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for other devices, we have a wonderful developer working on the Nexus 5 and its screen tearing problems in developer builds. It seems to be a bug between Mir and the Adreno drivers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you’d like to support our project financially, you can donate toward a specific device at &lt;a href=&quot;https://devices.ubports.com&quot;&gt;https://devices.ubports.com&lt;/a&gt; or give a monthly donation at &lt;a href=&quot;https://devices.ubports.com&quot;&gt;https://www.patreon.com/ubports&lt;/a&gt;. If you’d like to donate your time, check us out at #ubports on Freenode and we’ll find something that you can do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, happy holidays. And thank you. We’re looking forward to a great 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Dalton (UniversalSuperBox)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/2016/12/26/happy-holidays-from-ubports.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/2016/12/26/happy-holidays-from-ubports.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The StationDock</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;(Marius Quabeck at ubuntufun.de wrote about this first. Using Google Translate, I shamelessly ripped off a lot of his article. Give him some pageviews if you want to see the real source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://ubuntufun.de/2016/11/exklusiv-ein-station-dock-fuer-ubuntu-touch-mit-video/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since its inception, Ubuntu Touch has touted convergence: the ability to move between the phone or tablet display to a larger, more comfortable working display on command. With Mir and Unity 8 in a working state, it’s getting closer and closer to that every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That poses an important question: how do you get your phone screen onto the larger one? You can plug into the HDMI port on your phone… if you have one, and the number of phones with that option is quickly dwindling. So, your other option is Miracast. But Miracast introduces latency and artifacts into your transmission (especially in a RF-heavy area). This is acceptable for showing images or streaming video, but can get quite annoying for a desktop experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re announcing the StationDock project: a dock for your Ubuntu Touch smartphone. Plugging your phone in creates a small wired network between the Raspberry Pi in the dock and your phone, thanks to RNDIS. The phone then transmits Miracast packets over this connection, allowing reduced latency and a better overall experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dock features 2 USB ports, HDMI out, and an audio jack. It may or may not include a microphone jack in the finished product. Inside the (currently) 3D-printed enclosure is a Raspberry Pi and a large battery to charge your device and keep the dock running off the charger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll be posting more details, including our Kickstarter campaign, in the coming weeks. We hope that you’re as excited as we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for news about device ports, stay tuned! I’ll be writing another post shortly!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-UniversalSuperBox&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/2016/11/22/new-shiny.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/2016/11/22/new-shiny.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is UBPorts dead?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve been seeing a lot of questions on places like reddit.com/r/ubuntu asking if Ubuntu Touch or UBPorts are dead. We’re here to answer that once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a busy couple of weeks here at UBPorts. We’ve been trying our hardest to get a Nexus 5 devel build out the door and we need that to boot and work fine. We’re very close, so stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has also been a good amount of work done on the OPO and FP2 but not much publicly has been said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might ask, “Why is it taking so long?” Well, my good eager beaver, it’s because UBPorts switched to using CyanogenMod 12.1 instead of Android 4.4.2 as its base. As we manage to get it stable, it will hopefully enable more devices (all of them that have CyanogenMod 12.1 builds and a willing developer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has also been a lot going on prepairing for the soon to come ubucon, which, if all goes to plan, should be a very exciting even for ubports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working on documentation for various parts of the project and all of that work is going into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.ubports.com&quot;&gt;UBPorts Wiki&lt;/a&gt;. I’m trying to detail parts of the porting process that are frequently asked about in our IRC. If you have anything that you’d like to contribute, please feel free to add it to the Wiki!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I’ll end today with a call to action: if you own the Nexus 5X and are willing to help the porting effort, be sure to check &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.ubports.com/wiki/Nexus-5X-Developer-Information&quot;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; out! Of course, if you have any other device and a will to work with us, we will certainly welcome you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the community, we also have some videos from a user showing off the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCf7MNr0xlN6g36HNiXrvLmw&quot;&gt;FairPhone 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. Hopefully I’ll get better at writing these posts eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/UniversalSuperBox&quot;&gt;UniversalSuperBox&lt;/a&gt;
(And Chloe too)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/2016/11/11/is-ubports-dead.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/2016/11/11/is-ubports-dead.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coming Soon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.ubports.com/assets/2016/10/27-teaser-photo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;teaserimage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ubucon.org/en/events/ubucon-europe/&quot;&gt;See it Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/2016/10/27/coming-soon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/2016/10/27/coming-soon.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Calling For BETA Testers</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;calling-for-beta-testers&quot;&gt;Calling for Beta Testers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we are pushing out a new OTA to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;devel_rc-proposed&lt;/code&gt; for the Nexus 5, followed by the OnePlus One and the FairPhone 2 soon after, this is for people to test the software, so don’t expect anything incredibly stable, we do expect this build to not be far from stable though, but we’d rather be safe then sorry, to make sure the software is up to par it will only leave &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;devel_rc-proposed&lt;/code&gt; after 3 people confirm that it’s working to a high enough standard, so if you are a tester, please go install &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;devel_rc-proposed&lt;/code&gt;, fill in this &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.ubuntu.com/~mariogrip/Ubuntu-touch/UbportsQATesting5.1.pdf&quot;&gt;document&lt;/a&gt; and email it to ubports@lists.launchpad.net&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 18:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/beta/2016/10/21/BETA-Test-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/beta/2016/10/21/BETA-Test-1.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Beta</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello World!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone, and welcome to the UBPorts Blog! This is where we’ll be posting news and updates on the progress of porting your favorite mobile OS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, first things first: most of this blog will be written ‘by proxy,’ that is, Mariogrip will compile developer notes and snippets and the blog team will deal with making it look presentable for all of you. The reason for this is mainly due to an extreme time shortage in Mariogrip’s life. If we get the translation wrong from time to time, we’re sorry and we’ll get better next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way, it’s time for some good news!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;old-device-development&quot;&gt;Old Device Development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There isn’t much to be spoken of here, at least not on the surface. Marius is working on squashing bugs in devel_rc-proposed builds on the Nexus 5, and other devices will piggyback on that success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-device-development&quot;&gt;New Device Development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been some recent development by community members on several new and strange devices, including the HTC One X (endeavoru) and LG Nexus 5X (bullhead). Both systems boot but are at different stages of graphical functionality. Mir crashes quickly on the One X and the 5X never gets past the “Google” bootloader screen. Both devices are alive, though, as it is possible to get a debug console.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to contribute toward development of either of these devices (code, debugging, a shoulder to cry on) or any others, you can try asking in #ubports on Freenode. Please, though, don’t ask for status reports there. This blog will become the go-to place for that information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-documentation&quot;&gt;New Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re encouraging all porters and community members to post on the &lt;a href=&quot;wiki.ubports.com&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;. If you have any porting information you’d like to share with the community, we’d love to see your documentation. Some awesome new pages include &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.ubports.com/wiki/Commandline-networking-with-Network-Manager&quot;&gt;Commandline networking with Network Manager&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.ubports.com/wiki/Installing-Your-Build-With-Rootstock&quot;&gt;Installing your Build with Rootstock&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s about all for now, everyone. We hope to be able to bring you more good news next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/UniversalSuperBox&quot;&gt;UniversalSuperBox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/2016/10/12/hello-world.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/2016/10/12/hello-world.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
