<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UBports blog</title>
    <description>UBports blog. Ubuntu touch porting to android devices
</description>
    <link>http://blog.ubports.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.ubports.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 00:30:22 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 00:30:22 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Calling For BETA Testers</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;calling-for-beta-testers&quot;&gt;Calling for Beta Testers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we are pushing out a new OTA to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;devel_rc-proposed&lt;/code&gt; for the Nexus 5, followed by the OnePlus One and the FairPhone 2 soon after, this is for people to test the software, so don’t expect anything incredibly stable, we do expect this build to not be far from stable though, but we’d rather be safe then sorry, to make sure the software is up to par it will only leave &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;devel_rc-proposed&lt;/code&gt; after 3 people confirm that it’s working to a high enough standard, so if you are a tester, please go install &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;devel_rc-proposed&lt;/code&gt;, fill in this &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.ubuntu.com/~mariogrip/Ubuntu-touch/UbportsQATesting5.1.pdf&quot;&gt;document&lt;/a&gt; and email it to ubports@lists.launchpad.net&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 00:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/beta/2016/10/22/BETA-Test-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/beta/2016/10/22/BETA-Test-1.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Beta</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello World!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone, and welcome to the UBPorts Blog! This is where we’ll be posting news and updates on the progress of porting your favorite mobile OS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, first things first: most of this blog will be written ‘by proxy,’ that is, Mariogrip will compile developer notes and snippets and the blog team will deal with making it look presentable for all of you. The reason for this is mainly due to an extreme time shortage in Mariogrip’s life. If we get the translation wrong from time to time, we’re sorry and we’ll get better next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way, it’s time for some good news!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;old-device-development&quot;&gt;Old Device Development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There isn’t much to be spoken of here, at least not on the surface. Marius is working on squashing bugs in devel_rc-proposed builds on the Nexus 5, and other devices will piggyback on that success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-device-development&quot;&gt;New Device Development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been some recent development by community members on several new and strange devices, including the HTC One X (endeavoru) and LG Nexus 5X (bullhead). Both systems boot but are at different stages of graphical functionality. Mir crashes quickly on the One X and the 5X never gets past the “Google” bootloader screen. Both devices are alive, though, as it is possible to get a debug console.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to contribute toward development of either of these devices (code, debugging, a shoulder to cry on) or any others, you can try asking in #ubports on Freenode. Please, though, don’t ask for status reports there. This blog will become the go-to place for that information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-documentation&quot;&gt;New Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re encouraging all porters and community members to post on the &lt;a href=&quot;wiki.ubports.com&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;. If you have any porting information you’d like to share with the community, we’d love to see your documentation. Some awesome new pages include &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.ubports.com/wiki/Commandline-networking-with-Network-Manager&quot;&gt;Commandline networking with Network Manager&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.ubports.com/wiki/Installing-Your-Build-With-Rootstock&quot;&gt;Installing your Build with Rootstock&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s about all for now, everyone. We hope to be able to bring you more good news next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/UniversalSuperBox&quot;&gt;UniversalSuperBox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/2016/10/12/hello-world.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/2016/10/12/hello-world.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;Tom&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &#39;Hi, Tom&#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 16:14:10 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/jekyll/update/2016/10/11/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/jekyll/update/2016/10/11/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
