<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UBports blog</title>
    <description>UBports blog. Ubuntu touch porting to android devices
</description>
    <link>http://blog.ubports.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.ubports.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 16:44:28 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 16:44:28 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>UBports Community Q&amp;A: April 29, 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/UvfeCj6SRGg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.ubports.com/assets/2017/04/29-dalton.png&quot; alt=&quot;livestream&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another fortnight, another Q&amp;amp;A session! Watch it &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/UvfeCj6SRGg&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or read on for a quick summary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-been-happening&quot;&gt;What’s been happening?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First off all, a big thank you to all our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/ubports/posts&quot;&gt;Patreon&lt;/a&gt; supporters. We are currently recieving just over 600$ in donations every month, so this helps a lot in making UBports sustainable. A big high five for that!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://halium.org/&quot;&gt;Halium&lt;/a&gt; is in the air! We joined forces with the Plasma Mobile and Sailfish OS community to create a common base for non-android Linux-based mobile operating systems. We will basically create a unified way of implementing Libhybris, a library that allows us to directly address the Android hardware abstraction layer (HAL). That way, the future of porting will be making Halium work on a device and then just installing any mobile operating system that works with it. A prototype on the Nexus 5 is in the works right now, and it’s gonna be &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt;! Bright future ahead, everyone!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The development team has been working towards building a custom Ubuntu 16.04 rootfs. To make that possible, we now have two extra ARM-servers to speed up compilation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are aware that the community wants to see an official roadmap. That is already in the works and will be published soon.For now, you can go stalk us on on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://trello.com/ubports&quot;&gt;trello boards&lt;/a&gt;, even though some project management resources still need to be moved there.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new website is in the works! Look out for that next week.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We now have some further insights into Canonical’s plans: The official devices will receive security-updates until the end of June 2017 (We will of course release new images before that) and the click store will stay open until the end of this year. We might even keep it in the images for now, so have a little less pressure to create a seamless transition. We will eventually move all the free and open-source apps to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://openstore.ubports.com/&quot;&gt;openstore&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;call-to-arms&quot;&gt;Call to ARMs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, pun intended. No, I am not sorry. We know that the community is eager to help us and we apologize that we don’t have the resources to enable you to do that. But we actually have a few things that we can use your help with right now:
- We need a decent &lt;strong&gt;build management tool&lt;/strong&gt;. We’re looking for a tool that hooks into our system image server and let’s us promote builds from our development channel to the slower-moving channels. There is no requirement on language for this, though Marius might kill us if we accept PHP.
- If you know &lt;strong&gt;Groovy&lt;/strong&gt; and have some experience writing plugins for &lt;strong&gt;Jenkins&lt;/strong&gt;, please get in touch with us! We are looking for a way to automate taking on new devices. Your program will need to check a GitHub repository for files and take build instructions from them.
- You’re a &lt;strong&gt;web designer&lt;/strong&gt; and you know &lt;strong&gt;NodeJS&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Pug&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/strong&gt;? Awesome! Care to look at our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ubports/ubports.com/tree/mariogrip/new-design&quot;&gt;website redesign&lt;/a&gt;? Just make it look good, that’s all we ask for. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your help, now let’s answer some questions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-going-on-with-the-station-dock&quot;&gt;What’s going on with the Station Dock?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Ubucon Europe last year, we announced a nifty little device called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ubports.com/2016/11/22/new-shiny.html&quot;&gt;Station Dock&lt;/a&gt;, a Raspberry Pi based gadget that helps with convergence on devices that don’t have wired HDMI out. While there is a working prototype and everything would be ready to go, managing a Crowd-funding campaign and building hardware is a lot of work and we are unsure if &lt;em&gt;more work&lt;/em&gt; is what we need right now. We yet have to decide if we want to follow through with the campaign or just open-source the plans and software right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-about-the-stable-builds-you-said-they-were-going-to-be-published-this-week&quot;&gt;What about the stable builds? You said they were going to be published this week?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that we’ll have to do in the future is tell the community when we are going to be able to meet deadlines like that, and in this case we are not. There are still &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.ubports.com/wiki/UBports-Bug-Trackers&quot;&gt;some bugs we want to fix before release&lt;/a&gt;, so there is a little delay. An unstable stable release would be a little weird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-legacy-mode-and-why-are-the-old-official-canonical-devices-included-in-it&quot;&gt;What is “Legacy Mode,” and why are the old official Canonical devices included in it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The older devices will be on life support and the actual work will happen in the non-legacy branch, but we will still provide critical security-updates and merge bug-fixes from the community. This way you will still be able to use your phone with Ubuntu Touch if you own one of the official devices, but the cool and shiny new features will probably only land in the non-legacy branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are putting devices here because we don’t have any other choice. The official devices from BQ and Meizu have closed Android device trees. Because of this, we aren’t able to fix bugs in hardware enablement or add new features dependant on the kernel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-will-i-be-able-to-reflash-my-phone&quot;&gt;When will I be able to reflash my phone?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re working as fast as we can. Hopefully the new images will be out there in one or two weeks. We managed to get some blockers out the way and are working on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;will-the-nokia-here-agps-service-stay-in-the-builds-for-the-former-official-devices&quot;&gt;Will the Nokia HERE AGPS service stay in the builds for the former official devices?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s still a question mark there due to licensing issues. If we are allowed to keep HERE, it will stay in the builds, if not, we will try to replace it with Mozilla AGPS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;will-you-take-over-the-existing-bugreports-from-launchpad-or-does-everything-have-to-be-reported-again&quot;&gt;Will you take over the existing bugreports from launchpad or does everything have to be reported again?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We won’t touch that before we have to, because we don’t want to break all the links and we really don’t want to report everything again. Some may be moved in the future, but that’s yet to be decided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-will-happen-to-the-application-lifecycle-restrictions-of-ubuntu-touch&quot;&gt;What will happen to the application lifecycle restrictions of Ubuntu Touch?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s too early to decide that yet, once there are new images, we will think about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;will-you-host-the-ubuntu-touch-documentation-on-you-own-wiki-or-will-that-stay-where-it-is-right-now&quot;&gt;Will you host the Ubuntu Touch documentation on you own wiki or will that stay where it is right now?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now it will stay in the Ubuntu Wiki, and if we’re not forced to move it we won’t. This may change in the future, though. Limited resources, you all know the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;will-you-support-multirom&quot;&gt;Will you support MultiROM?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably not. We haven’t played with MultiROM in over a year and it would be too much work to fix it right now, so if you have MultiROM and you want Ubuntu Touch, you will have to choose one OS. That ¡*&lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt;*! change with Halium, but that’s not carved in stone yet and we won’t make any promises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You still have questions that have not been answered yet? No problem, our next Q&amp;amp;A will happen on Saturday, May 13 at 6 PM UTC. If you won’t be able to catch us live, be sure to get your questions in beforehand in the comment section down below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it for this time, make sure to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s-_L3J6EvgY&quot;&gt;catch the next one&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to discuss this or tell us how stupid we are, you can do that on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.ubports.com&quot;&gt;UBports forums&lt;/a&gt; or in &lt;a href=&quot;https://ubports.com/telegram&quot;&gt;our Telegram supergroup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take care and have a good one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Jan&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/2017/04/29/community-qa.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/2017/04/29/community-qa.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Resolution to Agree On</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a response to the recent open letter sent to the UBports project leadership as well as the response to it. So, in a way, it’s a response-response. A meta response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-egg-is-on-our-face&quot;&gt;The egg is on our face.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this section, “We” refers to the writers of the open letter. In later sections it will refer to the UBports team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we need to apologize for the way the original complaints were sent. What came after clicking the “Publish” button was a blowback more extreme than any of the signers expected, but we were the ones who clicked it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Utlimately, the reasoning behind the letter was to bring the project together more. That might sound counterintuitive, but conflict management isn’t our strong suit. In the end, the letter has suited its purpose, but not without cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re sorry to Marius Gripsgard for the personal stress and hardship caused. We’re sorry to everyone that was confused or scared by the letter and what it might have meant for the project. The whole team here has learned a lot about each other in the past few days. In some cases, more than we would have liked. This will make us stronger in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suffice it to say that we will never handle our gripes like this again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-happens-now&quot;&gt;What happens now?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On April 25, 2017, two signers of the open letter and Marius Gripsgard met to discuss the letter and the methods of sending it. We reached a lot of agreements and found the places where communication broke down leading to the fiasco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;our-project-image-is-now-a-concern&quot;&gt;Our project image is now a concern.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we don’t start acting more professional, we aren’t going to get any professional developers on board. This is an obvious problem that mostly points to the UBports team and not the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A topic of discussion that came up quickly was our habit of announcing projects or showing off screenshots of things that don’t really work yet, then not following up on them. When this happens in the future, we’ll be sure to specify the nature of these projects better: whether they are official from the project or simply a developer’s toy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are going to be moderating our chat rooms and forum a bit better starting now, trying to keep the discourse professional yet community-oriented. What does that mean for you? Almost nothing. We are okay with light banter and respectful disagreement in UBports communication. We are not okay with communication that becomes rude, insulting, or blatantly off-topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-team-of-people-to-make-the-decisions-not-one-person&quot;&gt;A team of people to make the decisions, not one person.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The developers have the power. Decisions that are minor to the user, such as how we decide to implement a display server, will be discussed among the developers. However, decisions that change our users’ phones appearance or function will be discussed more openly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both cases, we have agreed to not make snap decisions from only one person. The developer team must agree when it is going to take on a project. The developer team will then communicate this with the Community team or the community directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the long term, we have a better solution to ensure proper decision making and project governance. We’ll announce it when it’s ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-sense-of-community-a-listening-atmosphere-between-developers-teams-and-the-people-who-support-us&quot;&gt;A sense of community, a listening atmosphere between developers, teams, and the people who support us.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biweekly Q&amp;amp;A sessions are still happening. At the beginning of these, we will recap what different teams have been doing since the last Q&amp;amp;A. After that, we will launch into the community’s questions and answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internally, we will improve our communication so this situation won’t happen again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-project-roadmap-that-we-follow&quot;&gt;A project roadmap that we follow&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a combination of kanban boards and Launchpad blueprints, we will create a list of short-term and long-term goals to achieve. We will include the information that people can use to contribute to these goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stick-to-these-changes-for-more-than-a-week&quot;&gt;Stick to these changes for more than a week&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time will tell on this one. We’re confident in ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-things-that-we-learned&quot;&gt;Other things that we learned&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are interesting snippets that were written in the meeting notes. They have no bearing on the rest of this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During a discussion about hit-by-a-bus syndrome, we learned that, “Buses come in many forms.” -Jan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we somehow got onto a discussion of cats and aircraft, Marius proudly proclaimed that, “If I was a cat on a plane, I would die from stress.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also learned that we should display a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;PHP WARNING!&lt;/code&gt; before talking about that language, otherwise Marius might explode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case that last section didn’t make it obvious enough, we all had a good time talking to each other after the initial awkwardness passed. A lot of the issues that we faced stemmed from communication breakdowns between project leadership and community members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are going to create the best mobile OS that we can. We aren’t letting a little disagreement stop us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/2017/04/26/a-resolution-to-agree-on.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/2017/04/26/a-resolution-to-agree-on.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>UBports Community Q&amp;A: April 15, 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.ubports.com/assets/2017/04/15-marius.png&quot; alt=&quot;supercoolquestions&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today marked another Q&amp;amp;A session in the books. You can find it right over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gNKxMiAnO1I&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; on our shiny new Youtube channel! The following are the majority of asked questions and a summary of their answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to discuss, you can come to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ubports.com/telegram&quot;&gt;our Telegram group&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.ubports.com&quot;&gt;forums&lt;/a&gt;, or you can post a comment using the below Disqus embed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you all for your support! Without further ado, here’s the summary!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;will-you-support-old-official-devices&quot;&gt;Will you support old official devices?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes. All devices but the Pro 5 and M10 will be in “legacy” mode, getting critical bugfixes and security updates. These will be in-between due to their closed Android source tree.
We have mirrored the system-image-server so we can host the old images at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-will-the-official-devices-be-updated&quot;&gt;How will the official devices be updated?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They will probably require a reflash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;which-device-should-i-buy&quot;&gt;Which device should I buy?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should probably buy one of the stable devices: Nexus 5, Fairphone 2, or Oneplus One.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-will-there-be-new-ports&quot;&gt;When will there be new ports?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we have the infrastructure in place to service new devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-happens-to-the-core-apps&quot;&gt;What happens to the core apps?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re moving them to GitHub. After our build infrastructure works, we’ll work on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-will-you-do-with-the-ubuntu-store&quot;&gt;What will you do with the Ubuntu store?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re forking the OpenStore at openstore.ubports.com. We will ask app developers if they would like to place their apps on this store. Otherwise we cannot move the apps. They can be forked and placed on our new&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-will-you-do-with-ubuntu-one-services-and-push-notifications&quot;&gt;What will you do with Ubuntu One services and push notifications?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We might use Ubuntu One sign-in services. Push notifications are going to be handled by applications rather than our servers. We don’t want that data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-the-future-hold-for-the-sdk&quot;&gt;What does the future hold for the SDK?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making a decision on that is on our todo list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-we-still-want-to-make-mir-run-on-top-of-wayland-if-canonical-is-going-to-keep-working-on-mir&quot;&gt;Do we still want to make Mir run on top of Wayland, if Canonical is going to keep working on Mir?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canonical is still maintaining Mir for IoT applications like digital signage. We expect that this means that the desktop and mobile focus will be lost. We still want to run Mir on top of Wayland to give ourselves and Yunit more options in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-plan-for-sync-services&quot;&gt;What is the plan for sync services?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would love to have sync services, but we need to have more boxes checked before we can worry about that part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;does-anbox-fit-into-your-plans&quot;&gt;Does Anbox fit into your plans?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You bet! Anbox works on the Oneplus One already, it will come to devices that can support it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;will-anbox-send-notifications-through-the-ubuntu-system&quot;&gt;Will Anbox send notifications through the Ubuntu system?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a lot we need to fix related to the system and notifications. It’s something we would like to tackle but this is a long term fix, it wont be in the short term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;will-you-ship-the-google-play-services-with-anbox&quot;&gt;Will you ship the Google Play Services with Anbox?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, we are not legally allowed to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/2017/04/15/community-qa.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/2017/04/15/community-qa.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>UBports Community Q&amp;A: April 8, 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Friday, April 7th, 2017, we started what will be a long journey into the future. A core team meeting at 1800 UTC was quickly followed by a community Q&amp;amp;A. The Q&amp;amp;A is public for anyone to view. You can view it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MVEm4X2ptEk&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or continue reading for a list of the Q’s and A’s. Remember that as this is still an early time for our project, almost everything here is subject to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;two-crashes-and-we-finally-arrived-at-hangouts-on-air&quot;&gt;Two crashes and we finally arrived at Hangouts on Air.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After crashing both jitsi.org and talky.io, yesterday’s UBports Q&amp;amp;A started with Mariogrip summing up what happened so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our short-term plan is to keep Unity 8 and Mir as is. We need to learn how to build these projects into system-image-server through automated means. We will also look into running Mir on top of Wayland as a stop-gap during the Yunit (unity8org) transition to qtWayland (if that happens, their community hasn’t decided yet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We DO NOT want to be maintaining a display server. By moving to Wayland we get native Libhybris support, meaning we should be able to work directly on the upstream libhybris. Until that is possible, though, we will ensure that our infrastructure can support our OS: We need better updates and some release policy changes: devel (nightly), rc-proposed (weekly), and stable (manual push), details TBD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We plan to support existing devices, but they’ll be in “legacy mode” due to hardware limitations. They’ll get small updates and bugfixes on the current 15.04 base, but will probably not make the jump to 16.04. UBports will also not provide Android base updates, though we haven’t planned these for our current stable devices either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-qa&quot;&gt;The Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-what-about-the-bq-m10&quot;&gt;Q: What about the bq M10?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Because this device is more powerful and still very usable, we’ll probably make it an “official” device rather than a “legacy” one. This means that it will get whatever new OS we build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-what-about-the-unity-8-desktop-experience&quot;&gt;Q: What about the Unity 8 desktop experience?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: We need a desktop experience since that’s the important part of convergence. We won’t develop more on Mir, but Unity 8 must be maintained for the important convergence goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-how-can-i-help-if-i-want-to-do-qa-or-testing&quot;&gt;Q: How can I help if I want to do QA or testing?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Right now we have a Google Form that will lead you through all the testing steps, but we need a better solution. More documentation needed. Just using your device and reporting bugs that you find is a very good solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-what-will-happen-to-the-notification-servers-and-the-ubuntu-one-dependant-services&quot;&gt;Q: What will happen to the notification servers and the Ubuntu One dependant services?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: We can continue to use OpenID through Canonical (Ubuntu One), but we’ll remove the server components from the OS since we want to redefine the notification service. The notification service is FAR too closed for our liking right now. We’re going to focus on usability rather than confinement since we’re breaking the current security model anyway. Using old Android kernels is the worst security flaw we have and there’s no way we’re going to make that go away soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-wait-so-confinement-is-going-away&quot;&gt;Q: Wait, so confinement is going away?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: No, but we’re going to make the system more open and usable rather than locked down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-why-arent-we-collaborating-with-yunithttpsyunitio&quot;&gt;Q: Why aren’t we collaborating with &lt;a href=&quot;https://yunit.io&quot;&gt;Yunit&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: We are having conversations with them. They want more desktop focus while we have more mobile focus. Both projects benefit from the other’s work. Having two forks of Unity 8 makes no sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-will-we-collaborate-with-mer-or-plasma-mobile&quot;&gt;Q: Will we collaborate with Mer or Plasma Mobile?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: It’s still on the table. It makes sense for all of us to work together on a common Android base and build our own distributions on top of that. Our communities could all work together and a single device enablement would open it up to lots of new OS’s. Working together means more success for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-youve-split-ubports-contributors-into-teams-whats-the-goal-of-this&quot;&gt;Q: You’ve split UBports contributors into teams. What’s the goal of this?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: A more structured project means that we all have a say and all have a defined purpose. Having different teams means that a team can make a decision faster than if we needed every contributor to agree. We also split into multiple group chats so we can actually talk to each other without being buried.
We have the infrastructure, developer, communication, and QA teams. We’re looking at adding more. Also, the communication team is the best team and no one can say otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-will-the-open-store-continue&quot;&gt;Q: Will the Open Store continue?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: TODO. We’re going to either fork the store or maintain it since it’s shutting down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-how-will-you-finance-all-of-this&quot;&gt;Q: How will you finance all of this?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ubports.com/get-involved&quot;&gt;Donations&lt;/a&gt;. One-time Paypal donations and Patreon contributions are what will keep us going. Servers are going to be extremely expensive, devices aren’t getting cheaper either. Each member of the QA team will need most of our devices to test. We’re not worrying yet, but this will become a problem in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-can-we-hire-full-time-people&quot;&gt;Q: Can we hire full-time people?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: It’s in the future, but we would &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; to. It would make the project move much faster. A developer and a sysadmin allowing the developers to focus only on developing would be perfect. We don’t have the money for that yet. Or the legal knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-will-we-sell-devices-pre-installed-with-your-os&quot;&gt;Q: Will we sell devices pre-installed with your OS?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: That’s tricky. Legal issues like Qualcomm licensing would absolutely kill that business… unless we ship the device without modifying any of the proprietary blobs. Long story short, that’s out of our scope right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-what-happened-to-the-station-dock&quot;&gt;Q: What happened to the Station Dock?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: It still exists. It’s been postponed for an indefinite amount of time. It’s based on a Raspberry Pi so we might just release the firmware and call it a day… 
inb4 a Chinese company takes the software and ships it as closed-source, making a lot of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-are-we-following-canonicals-plan-or-making-our-own-os&quot;&gt;Q: Are we following Canonical’s plan or making our own OS?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: We’re following for now, but we may change direction quickly as we determine what went right and wrong with Ubuntu Touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-will-we-make-sailfish-os-apps-compatible-with-your-stuff&quot;&gt;Q: Will we make Sailfish OS apps compatible with your stuff?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Maybe? We’ll have very different design languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-will-we-support-snaps&quot;&gt;Q: Will we support snaps?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Yes, but legacy devices might not. We don’t think we’ll do the atomic system updates (Ubuntu Core), only apps. We have no idea how atomic updates would work with the Android ecosystem… our guess is that they probably wouldn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-will-we-fix-long-standing-critical-bugs-in-ubuntu-touch&quot;&gt;Q: Will we fix long-standing critical bugs in Ubuntu Touch?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: We’ll try to polish the OS as much as we can, But don’t expect OTA-16 anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-will-this-be-hard-without-canonical&quot;&gt;Q: Will this be hard without Canonical?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Yes and no. Since this has now become a community project, we’ve seen a lot less pushback and a lot of people stepping up to help. When Canonical was the only one developing Unity, people hated it. Now people are coming out of the woodwork to say that they loved where it was going and will miss it. We have seen around 400 new devices hitting our system image server since the news. There’s a strange effect that Canonical has on the Open Source community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-will-there-be-a-guide-for-porting-ubuntu-touch-on-the-ubports-website&quot;&gt;Q: Will there be a guide for porting Ubuntu Touch on the UBports website?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: You bet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-but-how-do-we-really-feel-about-unity-and-touch-being-dropped&quot;&gt;Q: But how do we really &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; about Unity and Touch being dropped?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: We understand that the project wasn’t making money and that Canonical as a company should make money. We really can’t argue with the decision and Canonical has given us no reason to harbor any ill will (We got to present at MWC! How cool is that!?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-will-we-be-using-stuff-from-firefox-os&quot;&gt;Q: Will we be using stuff from Firefox OS?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: We stole some of their AGPS stuff, if that counts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-will-we-keep-the-name&quot;&gt;Q: Will we keep the name?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Hard to say. No reason to change it yet, but once we further separate ourselves from Canonical we’ll probably change it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-will-we-continue-the-core-apps&quot;&gt;Q: Will we continue the core apps?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Yes, but in a feature freeze state unless the community is very willing to help. We need to sort out the bottom of the stack before we work on the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-can-we-mirror-the-core-apps-to-github-and-use-git-rather-than-bazaar&quot;&gt;Q: Can we mirror the core apps to GitHub (and use Git rather than Bazaar)?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Sure. Code hosting at GitHub is a bit more accessible than Launchpad so we totally understand where this question came from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-will-we-keep-using-launchpad&quot;&gt;Q: Will we keep using Launchpad?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Yes. The project management of Launchpad is more than a Kanban board. We like the bugs.launchpad.net more than Github’s issue tracker, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-will-we-consider-moving-to-gitlab&quot;&gt;Q: Will we consider moving to GitLab?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: If we wanted to use it for Git only, sure. But we don’t. So no. GitHub is simply a more accessible platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-are-we-coming-to-ubucon-europehttpsubuconparis&quot;&gt;Q: Are we coming to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ubucon.paris&quot;&gt;Ubucon Europe&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: YES! We’re going to be showing off all of our work that hasn’t happened yet! Go future us! WOOOOOH!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-snap-only-supports-kernel-310-and-above-how-will-you-support-older-phones&quot;&gt;Q: Snap only supports kernel 3.10 and above. How will you support older phones?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Backports and patches. Canonical has already started on this. (Dalton’s note: Snaps work on kernel 3.4 with a namespacing patch, they just don’t have confinement). Any newer devices that we port to will have kernel 3.10 or above anyway, so we’re not that concerned. We have a LOT to handle before we even consider this problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-are-there-more-updates-coming-to-the-current-ubports-devices&quot;&gt;Q: Are there more updates coming to the current UBports devices?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Yes. We are still focusing on our efforts to bring our stable devices to a good state with the Canonical Ubuntu Touch images. We’ve set the Stable release target for April 30th, but we might not hit that any more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;q-what-if-i-missed-the-qa-but-i-want-to-talk-to--yell-at-you&quot;&gt;Q: What if I missed the Q&amp;amp;A but I want to talk to / yell at you?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: You can get a hold of us in &lt;a href=&quot;https://ubports.com/telegram&quot;&gt;our Telegram supergroup&lt;/a&gt;. We also have a neat little Disqus embed that you can use on all of our blog posts! We’ll be holding more of these community Q&amp;amp;A’s in the future. Our next one should be in about two or three weeks, stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Dalton and Jan&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/2017/04/08/ubports-community-q-a.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/2017/04/08/ubports-community-q-a.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>UBports Developer&#39;s Meeting - March 29, 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.ubports.com/assets/2017/03/30-conferencecall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;conferencecall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday some users and developers from UBports got together online to discuss the project’s present and future goals. There was fun discussion, everyone’s drinks of choice (for all members for which it was legal), and plenty of cats in the webcam frame. We spent some time on a few topics that should be interesting to the community at large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;device-status&quot;&gt;Device Status&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our focus right now is on our three stable devices: The FairPhone 2, Oneplus One, and Nexus 5. We’re putting our efforts toward bringing these devices back to a fully working state. After that’s finished (which it is, mostly), we will push an image to the Stable channel. Gone will be the days where development channels are more functional and less buggy than stable! Prepare thy phone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;oneplus-one&quot;&gt;Oneplus One&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have too much to say about this one. The developers working on this device have been pretty quiet in the UBports Telegram chat, so I haven’t heard about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nexus-5&quot;&gt;Nexus 5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few dedicated community members ensured that the Nexus 5 is ready for prime time once again. We’re going to push a new build to Stable for this device very soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fairphone-2&quot;&gt;FairPhone 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Same story as the Nexus 5, but with a much larger community. Thanks to the support of Smoose (a Netherlandic technology company), we were able to bring this device to a stable state in record time. In this process, we fixed quite a few blocking bugs for the Oneplus One and Nexus 5. A shared base means something!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;near-future-goals&quot;&gt;Near Future Goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bug-reporting&quot;&gt;Bug Reporting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been a sticking point for users and developers alike. We’ve decided that &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; bug tracking for UBports devices will take place on Launchpad. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ubports.com/get-involved&quot;&gt;Get Involved&lt;/a&gt; page for more information. Feel free to report bugs in UBports websites in their GitHub repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;polish&quot;&gt;Polish&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next few weeks will be spent on polishing our stable devices before shipping an image to the Stable channel. After that, we’ll move on to making the websites and wiki nicer. We hope that you’ll love how everything looks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;farther-future-goals&quot;&gt;Farther Future Goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These come after the near future goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-base&quot;&gt;New Base&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that an Android 5.1 (CyanogenMod 12.1) base limits us from porting Ubuntu to new devices. Because of this, we will begin work on a LineageOS 14.1 base. This doesn’t mean that current devices are abandoned, it will simply lay the groundwork for future devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-ubuntu&quot;&gt;New Ubuntu&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu 15.04 is almost entirely abandoned. Full stop. The only updates that Canonical has promised are for security. We need to move on from 15.04 as soon as possible. The 16.04 Touch images seem like a good place to jump, even though they aren’t currently functional. This will give us a platform that’s able to run Snaps &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Clicks, allowing us to move on to Ubuntu Personal when it comes around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve decided that, if possible, the FP2 will be our Ubuntu 16.04 testing device. We need to get snapd running on it first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-device&quot;&gt;New Device&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where we had the least success. Our dream device for porting Ubuntu and showing it off meets a few requirements: it has MHL, Slimport, or a dedicated HDMI port; it is available in the US as well as the rest of the world (official Ubuntu devices got the second part right); and it is powerful enough to make convergence shine. The Galaxy S8 announcement came at the perfect time, we’re just interested in how friendly Samsung will be to developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any suggestions for this miracle device, we’re all ears in our Telegram group (you can grab the link from the MOTD of #ubports on Freenode for now).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-things&quot;&gt;Other Things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll be removing the devel_rc-proposed channel soon. Four channels is a ridiculous amount for a project of our size. System-image-server has the ability to redirect a device to another channel without user intervention, so there’s nothing you’ll need to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, Even though https://stats.ubports.com/ can’t be guaranteed to be accurate, it is still an impressive look at the dynamics of our project. With just a small team of developers and a hefty amount of word of mouth, we’ve gotten really far. Thank you for your support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Dalton&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 17:50:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/2017/03/30/ubports-developer-meeting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/2017/03/30/ubports-developer-meeting.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is Ubuntu Touch Dead?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With news that dawned recently we’re expecting an influx of people joining our IRC to ask if we’re going to quit porting Ubuntu Touch now that it’s been announced to be dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, it’s not dead. Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=Ubuntu-Phone-Snap-Hold&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; over at Phoronix for a better look at the issue. Basically, Ubuntu Touch is just going to be rolled into Ubuntu Personal, the Snap-based version of Ubuntu. We’re going to start working on this as we have time, but it’s very experimental right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canonical is trying to focus their resources on Snaps, Unity 8, and Mir. We understand this and are not at all upset. It will bring the project forward as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, you guys should check out the Ubuntu Touch bountysource. You can find our tracker &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bountysource.com/trackers/45573416-ubports-android&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. There isn’t much there yet, but I for one find merit in having it around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the FP2 community, we also have a video showing our ability to place a call from a FP2 over GSM! Check it out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bz43mNw4AtU&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s about it for today. Ubuntu Touch is not dead. Come get in touch with us at #ubports on Freenode or the forum if you have any questions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Dalton (UniversalSuperBox)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/2017/01/06/is-ubuntu-touch-dead.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/2017/01/06/is-ubuntu-touch-dead.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy Holidays from UBPorts! (And FP2 fun!)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We here at UBPorts hope that you’re having/had an excellent set of holidays. As the year comes to a close, we’d like to thank all of our patrons, donors, and developers. You are what makes this project happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been busy around here, of course. Marius has returned for winter holiday at his school and my dashboard is looking busier than ever… an excellent sight when my name filled it up not too long ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d like to thank Smoose, a Netherlandic company specializing in open source software, for providing several Fairphone 2 smartphones to our developer community. Because of their generous donation, I have lots of news about the device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current daily builds for the Fairphone 2 have everything that you’ll find on &lt;a href=&quot;https://devices.ubports.com/#/FP2&quot;&gt;the device page&lt;/a&gt; PLUS some basic GSM support. You are able to connect to a GSM network with SIM 1 at least (I don’t have a second to test), send and receive SMS, and Marius reports that he has calling in a very experimental stage, though this may not be on system-image-server at the time of this writing. Mobile data doesn’t work quite yet, but we’re working on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To flash the development build, first note that it is not very stable and things break quite often. Now that that’s out of the way, you’ll need to first flash the recovery.img from &lt;a href=&quot;https://seafile.nigle.nl/d/62d505f0a7/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;,
Then run these commands:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
adb shell mount -a &amp;amp;&amp;amp;
adb shell mount /cache &amp;amp;&amp;amp;
ubuntu-device-flash --server=http://system-image.ubports.com touch --channel=ubuntu-touch/devel_rc-proposed --device=FP2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Edit: I had to put them in this terrible block because this Jekyll theme is annoying)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for other devices, we have a wonderful developer working on the Nexus 5 and its screen tearing problems in developer builds. It seems to be a bug between Mir and the Adreno drivers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you’d like to support our project financially, you can donate toward a specific device at &lt;a href=&quot;https://devices.ubports.com&quot;&gt;https://devices.ubports.com&lt;/a&gt; or give a monthly donation at &lt;a href=&quot;https://devices.ubports.com&quot;&gt;https://www.patreon.com/ubports&lt;/a&gt;. If you’d like to donate your time, check us out at #ubports on Freenode and we’ll find something that you can do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, happy holidays. And thank you. We’re looking forward to a great 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Dalton (UniversalSuperBox)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/2016/12/26/happy-holidays-from-ubports.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/2016/12/26/happy-holidays-from-ubports.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The StationDock</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;(Marius Quabeck at ubuntufun.de wrote about this first. Using Google Translate, I shamelessly ripped off a lot of his article. Give him some pageviews if you want to see the real source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://ubuntufun.de/2016/11/exklusiv-ein-station-dock-fuer-ubuntu-touch-mit-video/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since its inception, Ubuntu Touch has touted convergence: the ability to move between the phone or tablet display to a larger, more comfortable working display on command. With Mir and Unity 8 in a working state, it’s getting closer and closer to that every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That poses an important question: how do you get your phone screen onto the larger one? You can plug into the HDMI port on your phone… if you have one, and the number of phones with that option is quickly dwindling. So, your other option is Miracast. But Miracast introduces latency and artifacts into your transmission (especially in a RF-heavy area). This is acceptable for showing images or streaming video, but can get quite annoying for a desktop experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re announcing the StationDock project: a dock for your Ubuntu Touch smartphone. Plugging your phone in creates a small wired network between the Raspberry Pi in the dock and your phone, thanks to RNDIS. The phone then transmits Miracast packets over this connection, allowing reduced latency and a better overall experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dock features 2 USB ports, HDMI out, and an audio jack. It may or may not include a microphone jack in the finished product. Inside the (currently) 3D-printed enclosure is a Raspberry Pi and a large battery to charge your device and keep the dock running off the charger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll be posting more details, including our Kickstarter campaign, in the coming weeks. We hope that you’re as excited as we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for news about device ports, stay tuned! I’ll be writing another post shortly!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-UniversalSuperBox&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/2016/11/22/new-shiny.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/2016/11/22/new-shiny.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is UBPorts dead?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve been seeing a lot of questions on places like reddit.com/r/ubuntu asking if Ubuntu Touch or UBPorts are dead. We’re here to answer that once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a busy couple of weeks here at UBPorts. We’ve been trying our hardest to get a Nexus 5 devel build out the door and we need that to boot and work fine. We’re very close, so stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has also been a good amount of work done on the OPO and FP2 but not much publicly has been said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might ask, “Why is it taking so long?” Well, my good eager beaver, it’s because UBPorts switched to using CyanogenMod 12.1 instead of Android 4.4.2 as its base. As we manage to get it stable, it will hopefully enable more devices (all of them that have CyanogenMod 12.1 builds and a willing developer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has also been a lot going on prepairing for the soon to come ubucon, which, if all goes to plan, should be a very exciting even for ubports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working on documentation for various parts of the project and all of that work is going into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.ubports.com&quot;&gt;UBPorts Wiki&lt;/a&gt;. I’m trying to detail parts of the porting process that are frequently asked about in our IRC. If you have anything that you’d like to contribute, please feel free to add it to the Wiki!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I’ll end today with a call to action: if you own the Nexus 5X and are willing to help the porting effort, be sure to check &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.ubports.com/wiki/Nexus-5X-Developer-Information&quot;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; out! Of course, if you have any other device and a will to work with us, we will certainly welcome you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the community, we also have some videos from a user showing off the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCf7MNr0xlN6g36HNiXrvLmw&quot;&gt;FairPhone 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. Hopefully I’ll get better at writing these posts eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/UniversalSuperBox&quot;&gt;UniversalSuperBox&lt;/a&gt;
(And Chloe too)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/2016/11/11/is-ubports-dead.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/2016/11/11/is-ubports-dead.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coming Soon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.ubports.com/assets/2016/10/27-teaser-photo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;teaserimage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ubucon.org/en/events/ubucon-europe/&quot;&gt;See it Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.ubports.com/2016/10/27/coming-soon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.ubports.com/2016/10/27/coming-soon.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
